<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Piotr Wachulec</title>
    <link>https://wachulec.me/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Piotr Wachulec</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 11:53:40 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wachulec.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TLS says &#39;Hello!&#39;</title>
      <link>https://wachulec.me/posts/tls-says-hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 11:53:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wachulec.me/posts/tls-says-hello/</guid>
      <description>TLS is the protocol for encrypting the information during transporting them via the Internet. To connect the client and the server to use TLS protocol and set up the secure connection between them the below steps need to be done (we can call it as TLS handshake):
 The client sends &amp;lsquo;Hello&amp;rsquo; message to the server. The message contains the information about which versions of TLS or SSL protocols and which cryptographic alghoritms are supported by the client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#30DEVSTORIES - my knowledge, thoughts and experience</title>
      <link>https://wachulec.me/posts/30devstories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 08:30:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wachulec.me/posts/30devstories/</guid>
      <description>Intro In the Polish IT Community, we had a great initiative on Instagram inspired by Guys from these two profiles: @kjendrzyca and @devenv.pl. Through 30 days we were sharing short Instagram stories related to our dev live - we shared our knowledge, our thoughts, and our experience. If you would like to check stories of other participants - here is a link: https://30devstories.crd.co/ or https://30devstories.pl/.
In my Instagram stories, I shared much information related to C#/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No code app with Azure Storage, Event Grid and Logic App</title>
      <link>https://wachulec.me/posts/no-code-app-with-azure-storage-event-grid-logic-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 09:11:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wachulec.me/posts/no-code-app-with-azure-storage-event-grid-logic-app/</guid>
      <description>Intro On Instagram I got the nomination for #Hot16CodeChallange where in 72 h I had to prepare some fancy application in 16 lines of code. I cheated a little bit, because I didn&amp;rsquo;t write any line of code! In my solution I used Azure Storage, Azure Event Grid and Azure Logic App.
Business case Imagine that you have yours company site and you would like to hire new person to your company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature toggles in .NET Core and Azure</title>
      <link>https://wachulec.me/posts/feature-toggles-in-dotnet-core-and-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 10:42:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wachulec.me/posts/feature-toggles-in-dotnet-core-and-azure/</guid>
      <description>Intro Feature toggles is an mechanism which allows you to control features and manage them within your application. For instance if you want to disable some functionality you can to that by changing some part of configuration without redeployment, rebuild etc. In this post I will show you how to configure it in a few easy steps in .NET Core web application and Azure. At the end you will find repository with example code which you can test it on your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Unit Testing with .NET and Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://wachulec.me/posts/live-unit-testing-with-dotnet-and-visual-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 10:23:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wachulec.me/posts/live-unit-testing-with-dotnet-and-visual-studio/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I was looking for something related to unit tests in the Microsoft documentation. I came to the tab titled &amp;lsquo;Live unit testing&amp;rsquo; and I decided to check what is it. It is quite interesting, because why I have to click to run unit tests when I made small changes in code? We have the live reload functionality in frontend or some mobile technologies to see changes in the interface, so the developer don&amp;rsquo;t have manually click F5 to refresh the page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>