<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud on Piotr Wachulec</title><link>https://wachulec.me/tags/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud on Piotr Wachulec</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.1</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 11:14:08 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wachulec.me/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slack notifications on Azure budget consumption</title><link>https://wachulec.me/posts/slack-notifications-on-azure-budget-consumption/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 11:14:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wachulec.me/posts/slack-notifications-on-azure-budget-consumption/</guid><description>In my free time (I don&amp;rsquo;t have too much free time, to be honest 😋) I help my colleagues in the open-source project where juniors can learn something useful for their career. I started to deliver some infra for that stuff on Azure, but due to the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m paying for resources from my pocket, I want to have some nice notifications if something consumes a big amount of money and burns the budget.</description></item><item><title>How to manage resources in the external tenant in Azure?</title><link>https://wachulec.me/posts/how-to-manage-resources-in-the-external-tenant-in-azure/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 10:20:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wachulec.me/posts/how-to-manage-resources-in-the-external-tenant-in-azure/</guid><description>The case You want to manage resources in other tenants without additional workload around that like accounts creation for you and your teammates in the destination Azure tenant or disabling those accounts if someone leaves the team. Is there any solution for that?
The answer is: yes! And it is called Azure Lighthouse.
From docs:
Azure Lighthouse enables cross- and multi-tenant management, allowing for higher automation, scalability, and enhanced governance across resources and tenants.</description></item><item><title>#30DEVSTORIES - my knowledge, thoughts and experience</title><link>https://wachulec.me/posts/30devstories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 08:30:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wachulec.me/posts/30devstories/</guid><description>Intro In the Polish IT Community, we had a great initiative on Instagram inspired by Guys from these two profiles: @kjendrzyca and @devenv.pl. Through 30 days we were sharing short Instagram stories related to our dev live - we shared our knowledge, our thoughts, and our experience. If you would like to check stories of other participants - here is a link: https://30devstories.crd.co/ or https://30devstories.pl/.
In my Instagram stories, I shared much information related to C#/.</description></item></channel></rss>